Built to fight. Born to love.
Ferdinand is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Carlos Saldanha.
Ferdinand, a little bull, prefers sitting quietly under a cork tree just smelling the
flowers versus jumping around, snorting, and butting heads with other bulls.
As Ferdinand grows big and strong, his temperament remains mellow, but one day five men come to choose the
"biggest, fastest, roughest bull" for the bullfights in Madrid and Ferdinand is mistakenly chosen.
Based on the classic 1936 children's book by Munro Leaf.
Ferdinand (voice), played by John Cena.
Lupe (voice), played by Kate McKinnon.
Bones (voice), played by Anthony Anderson.
Valiente / Valiente's Father (voice), played by Bobby Cannavale.
Guapo (voice), played by Peyton Manning.
Una (voice), played by Gina Rodriguez.
Ferdinand  is a 2017 American animated comedy film directed
by Carlos Saldanha and written by Robert L.
Baird, Tim Federle, and Brad Copeland, loosely based on Munro Leaf and
Robert Lawson's 1936 children's book The Story of Ferdinand.
Produced by Blue Sky Studios, the film features the
voices of John Cena and Kate McKinnon.
The music for the film was composed by John Powell.
The story follows a gentle pacifist bull named Ferdinand who refuses to participate in bullfighting but is forced back
into the arena where his beliefs are challenged when he faces off against the world's greatest bullfighter.
Ferdinand premiered on December 10, 2017, in Los Angeles, and was theatrically
released in the United States on December 15, 2017 by 20th Century Fox.
It received mixed reviews from critics and underperformed domestically, but fared better
internationally, grossing $296 million worldwide against a production budget of $111 million.
Ferdinand received a nomination for Best Animated Feature at the 90th Academy Awards, as well as nominations at
the 75th Golden Globe Awards for Best Animated Feature Film and Best Original Song ("Home").
The film explores themes of friendship, spain,
madrid, spain, europe, anthropomorphism.
The tone is lighthearted.